firstsource.com 2019-04-12

# Firstsource Privacy Policy & Disclaimer

Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

**Overview**

Firstsource Solutions Limited (which expression means and includes its affiliates and subsidiaries) has created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate the company’s commitment to privacy. This Privacy Policy demonstrates Firstsource Solutions Limited’s (‘we’, ‘our’) information gathering and dissemination practices for [www.firstsource.com](https://www.firstsource.com/)

We take care to protect the privacy of users of Firstsource Solutions Limited website. Below is an explanation of how we process data about visitors to the website.

Firstsource Solutions Limited is a business processing outsource company with head offices in India, UK, Philippines and the United States.  India Head Office, New Link Road, Malad West, Paradigm B, 5th Floor, Mindspace, Mumbai 400 064. UK Head Office, Space One, 1 Beadon Road, London W6 0EA. United States Head Office, 1661 Lyndom Farm Court, Louisville, Kentucky 40223. Philippines Head Office, Plaza D, Northgate Cyberzone 5th Floor, Firstsource Building, Filinvest Alabang Muntinlupa City.

**Cookies**

To improve your experience on our site, we may use ‘cookies’. Cookies are an industry standard and most major web sites use them. A cookie is a small text file that our site may place on your computer as a tool to remember your preferences. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

**IP addresses**

IP addresses are used by your computer every time you are connected to the Internet. Your IP address is a number that is used by computers on the network to identify your computer. IP addresses are automatically collected by our web server as part of demographic and profile data known as “traffic data” so that data (such as the Web pages you request) can be sent to you.

**Google Analytics**

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage.

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described in Google’s Privacy Policy (https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) and for the purposes set out above. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the opt-out service provided by Google (https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Social media**

Firstsource also uses interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter and others. If you choose to “like” or “share” information from this website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your visits to this site with other Personal Information

**External links**

Our website may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. When you go to other websites from here, we advise you to be aware and read their privacy policy.

### **Information given by the user**

We may receive and store any information which you enter on our website or give us in any other way, such as:

  * By submitting a web form, you will give us information such as your name, phone number and email address to enable us to reply to you. This will be under the lawful basis of consent and will not be shared outside of Firstsource Solutions Limited.
  * If you are applying for a vacancy with us, please refer to the job vacancy privacy policy for further information on how your data will be used.

We do not share any personal information with any third parties. When completing a web form, we will store and process personal data.

**Case 1: Forms on the contact page marked “Suppliers”, “Recruitment”, “Employees”, “Media/Press”, “Investors”, “Analysts” and “Other”**

We will gather your name, phone number, email address, company and job title (if applicable), Firstsource office you wish to contact (if applicable), and an optional message.

Your details and message will be:  
a) sent via email to the relevant person within the organisation  
b) stored in our database for a period of no more than 60 days before permanent deletion

This information can be removed by request by contacting us.

**Case 2: All other web forms (excluding job applications)**

We will gather your name, phone number, email address, location down to city level, web page on which you filled out the form, actions taken on our website, company and job title, industry, the solutions you are interested in, and an optional message.

We will also ask in a clear manner for your consent to a) receive marketing communications, and, separately, b) receive personal emails from Firstsource employees, such as business development representatives. These options will either be presented as checkboxes, or be clearly indicated in the form title, e.g. “Sign up for our mailing list”

Your details and message will be stored in our marketing automation system indefinitely. If you opted in to receiving marketing communications, you will be added to the general mailing list and any other mailing lists based on your indicated industry and desired solutions. You may unsubscribe at any time by emailing marketing@firstsource.com or clicking “Unsubscribe” at the bottom of any marketing email.

If you opted in to receiving personal messages, your details and message will be sent to a relevant member of our business development team. Your details may also be stored in Salesforce, our CRM system.

By submitting a web form in this second case, you consent to the processing of data about you by ActiveCampaign in the manner described in ActiveCampaign’s Privacy Policy (https://help.activecampaign.com/hc/en-us/articles/218789997-Privacy-Policy) and for the purposes set out below. You can contact them at any time if you would like to access or edit your data or if you have any questions about your data and how they are using it (https://www.activecampaign.com/contact/)

By opting in to receive personal messages, you also consent to the processing of data about you by Salesforce in the manner described in Salesforce’s Privacy Policy (https://help.salesforce.com/articleView?id=Salesforce-Services-Trust-and-Compliance-Documentation&language=en_US&type=1) for the same purposes.

You can contact us at marketing@firstsource.com at any time to remove your information.

We will not, without your explicit consent, disclose to anyone outside of Firstsource Solutions Limited any personal information you provide to us when you visit the website.

The data we would like to collect via forms is:

Personal data type: | Source (where Firstsource obtained the personal data from if it has not been collected directly from you, the data subject):  
---|---  
First and last name | Data subject  
Email address | Data subject  
Phone number | Data subject  
Company | Data subject  
Job title | Data subject  
Firstsource office you wish to contact | Data subject  
Your industry * | Data subject  
How can we help / desired solutions * | Data subject  
Conversion page * | The page on which you submitted the form  
Past activity on our website * | Cookies  
Location (down to city level) * | IP address  
Marketing consent * | Data subject  
Sales consent * | Data subject  
Message | Data subject  
  
***  **Only relevant for forms in Case 2 (details above)

Automatic information

We may at some time, receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us, e.g. the use of cookies

**E-mail communications**

To help us make e-mails more useful and interesting, we often receive a confirmation when you open e-mail from Firstsource.com if your computer supports such capabilities.

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and our partners by reading the unsubscribe instructions located at the bottom of any e-mail they receive from us at any time.

**Information from Other Sources**

We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our account information.

**What do we use personal data for?**

We use personal data to provide you with information that you have requested, including marketing purposes, sales and to process online applications.

Firstsource collects information including your Internet Protocol address, which will be anonymised, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your query. This information is collected in the interest of identifying any issues with the site, to establish which areas of the website are used more frequently and to help improve the website.

Information provided through the web forms including name, email address and contact number will only be used for the purpose of the web form submission including new customer contact, media enquiries and marketing. This will be processed under the lawful basis of consent.

### Security

This website has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and/or alteration of information under our control. The data resides behind a firewall, with access restricted to our authorized personnel. We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data.

### Disclosure and transfer of personal information

Firstsource keeps your personal information confidential except where disclosure/transfer of personal information is required by an order under the law for the time being in force or by Government agencies including law enforcement agencies having authority of law, upon their request in writing, even without obtaining your consent.

However, sometimes Firstsource uses third parties to process your information. Firstsource requires these third parties to comply strictly with its instructions and not to further transfer your personal information.

Firstsource also requires that they do not use your personal information for their own business purposes, unless you have explicitly consented.

**Access to information and your rights**

You have the right to access the information held about you and the right to have any inaccuracies corrected in the personal data we hold about you by contacting [marketing@firstsource.com](mailto:marketing@firstsource.com).

  * Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you.
  * Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
  * Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply to have a right to restrict the processing.
  * Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation.
  * Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing.
  * Right to judicial review: in the event that Firstsource Solutions Limited refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined below.

**Complaints**

  * The details for each of these contacts are:

** ** | **Supervisory authority contact details** | **Data Protection Officer (DPO)**  
---|---|---  
Contact Name: | Information Commissioners Officer | Data Protection Officer  
Address line 1: | Wycliffe House | Space One  
Address line 2: | Water Lane | 1 Beadon Road  
Address line 3: | Wilmslow | London  
Address line 4: | Cheshire | W6 0EA  
Address line 5: | SK9 5AF |   
Telephone: | 01625 545 745 |   
  
### Contacting us

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, or your dealings with this website, you can contact [marketing@firstsource.com](mailto:marketing@firstsource.com) for clarifications.

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at Firstsource Solutions UK Limited, Space One, 1 Beadon Road, London, W6 0EA

UK Job Applicant Privacy Policy

## UK Job Applicant Privacy Policy

### 1\. Scope

All individuals applying for a job vacancy with Firstsource Solutions UK Limited

### 2\. Privacy notice

**Who are we?**

Firstsource Solutions UK Limited is a business processing outsource company who collects and stores personal information regarding employees, clients, and as an outsourcing solutions provider, our client’s customers. Firstsource Solutions UK Limited is committed to ensuring this data is collected and processed fairly, lawfully and in a transparent manner and commits to adhering to the statutory duty to comply with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Our UK Head Office address is Firstsource Solutions UK Limited, Space One, 1 Beadon Road, London, W6 0EA

Our Data Protection Officer can be contacted at

  * Firstsource Solutions UK Limited, Space One, 1 Beadon Road, London, W6 0EA

Personal data type: | Source (where Firstsource obtained the personal data from if it has not been collected directly from you, the data subject. Note if the personal data has been accessed from publicly accessible sources):  
---|---  
Name | Data Subject  
Address | Data Subject  
Email Address | Data Subject  
Gender | Data Subject  
Contact Number | Data Subject  
Date Of Birth | Data Subject  
Qualifications | Data Subject  
Employment History | Data Subject  
Reference Details | Data Subject  
Ethnicity | Data Subject  
Health Information | Data Subject  
Criminal Offence Details | Data Subject  
Credit Check Details | Data Subject  
Eligibility To Work Documentation | Data Subject  
  
The personal data we collect will be used for the following purposes:

  * We need to process data to take steps as part of the recruitment process, prior to entering a contract with you. We may also need to process your data to enter into a contract with you if you are successful in your application for employment.
  * In some cases, we need to process data to ensure that we are complying with our legal obligations. This includes eligibility to work documentation.

Our lawful basis for processing for the personal data:

  * Contract
  * Legal Obligation
  * Legitimate Interests
  * Article 9 for special category data. Article 9(2)(b) – employment.
  * Data Protection Bill – Schedule 1 Employment

Any legitimate interests pursued by us, or third parties we use, are as follows:

  * We process health information in the interest of providing reasonable adjustments.
  * We process ethnicity information in the interest of monitoring equality.

The special categories of personal data concerned are:

  * Ethnicity
  * Health Information
  * Gender
  * Community Background Information (Northern Ireland only)

### 2.2 Disclosure

Firstsource Solutions UK Limited will pass on your personal data to third parties during the recruitment process. The following third parties will receive your personal data for the following purpose(s) as part of the processing activities:

**Third country (non-EU)/international organisation** | **Safeguards in place to protect your personal data** | **Purpose**  
---|---|---  
Disclosure & Barring Service (DBS) UK | Information processed directly on the website by the recruitment team and stored securely on the access controlled website. | For the purpose of pre-employment criminal conviction checks for England and Wales.  
Disclosure Scotland | Information processed directly with Disclosure Scotland for background checks, criminal record and credit checks. | For the purpose of pre-employment checks in Scotland and Northern Ireland.  
Experian, UK | Information processed directly on Experian website which is access controlled and is also stored securely on the site. | For the purpose of pre-employment credit checks.  
Pass, UK | Information is processed directly through the Pass system by the data subject and held in an access controlled system. | For the purpose of job applications.  
Amris, UK | Information is processed directly through Amris by the data subject and held in an access controlled system. | For the purpose of job applications.  
Smart Hire, UK | Applicant Data is transferred from Amris to Smarthire. Smarthire is held on the Firstsource network and is access controlled. | To maintain applicant records and link to HRMS (SAP) system.  
  
### 2.3 Retention Period

For successful candidates Firstsource Solutions UK Limited will process personal data and will store the personal data for the length of your employment. In addition, further retention periods apply for Payroll and Recruitment information which will be held for up to 7 years after your employment ceases. Background checks for criminal convictions and credit checks will be completed on successful candidates and will be held on the Experian portal for 24 months. If you are unsuccessful in an application Firstsource Solutions UK Limited will retain your information for 1 year.

### 2.4 Your rights as a data subject

At any point while we are in possession of or processing your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights:

  * Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you.
  * Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.
  * Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply to have a right to restrict the processing.
  * Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation.
  * Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing.
  * Right to object to automated processing, including profiling – you also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling.
  * Right to judicial review: in the event that Firstsource Solutions UK Limited refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined below.

All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved in the processing of your personal data.

### 2.5 Complaints

In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by Firstsource Solutions UK Limited (or third parties above), or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint directly with the supervisory authority and Firstsource Solutions UK Limited’s Data Protection Officer.

The details for each of these contacts are:

** ** | **Supervisory authority contact details** | **Data Protection Officer (DPO)**  
---|---|---  
Contact Name: | Information Commissioners Officer | Data Protection Officer  
Address line 1: | Wycliffe House | Space One  
Address line 2: | Water Lane | 1 Beadon Road  
Address line 3: | Wilmslow | London  
Address line 4: | Cheshire | W6 0EA  
Address line 5: | SK9 5AF |   
Telephone: | 01625 545 745 |   
  
### 3\. Privacy Statement

_Personal data_

Under the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) personal data is defined as:

_How we use your information_

This privacy notice tells you how we will collect and use your personal data for the purposes of our recruitment process. The information collected will not be used for any other purpose than the recruitment process. If your application for employment is successful, personal data gathered during the recruitment process will be transferred to your HR file (electronic and paper based) and retained during the period of your employment and in some circumstances afterwards. The periods for which your data will be held should you become an employee will be provided to you in the privacy notice for employees. For unsuccessful applicants this data will be retained for 1 year.

_Why does  _ _Firstsource Solutions UK Limited_ _  need to collect and store personal data?_

As an employer we need to collect personal data for the purposes of employment, including recruitment, HR and payroll activities as well as managing performance. In any event, we are committed to ensuring that the information we collect and use is appropriate for this purpose, and does not constitute an invasion of your privacy.

_Will  _ _Firstsource Solutions UK Limited_ _  share my personal data with anyone else?_

We may pass your personal data on to third-party service providers contracted to Firstsource Solutions UK Limited in the course of dealing with you. Any third parties that we may share your data with are obliged to keep your details securely, and to use them only to fulfil the service they provide you on our behalf. When they no longer need your data to fulfil this service, they will dispose of the details in line with Firstsource Solutions UK Limited procedures.

_How will  _ _Firstsource Solutions UK Limited_ _  use the personal data it collects about me?_

Firstsource Solutions UK Limited will process (collect, store and use) the information you provide in a manner compatible with the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We will endeavour to keep your information accurate and up to date, and not keep it for longer than is necessary. Firstsource Solutions UK Limited is required to retain information in accordance with the law, such as information needed for income tax and audit purposes.

_Under what circumstances will  _ _Firstsource Solutions UK Limited_ _  contact me?_

Our aim is not to be intrusive, and we undertake not to ask irrelevant or unnecessary questions. Moreover, the information you provide will be subject to rigorous measures and procedures to minimise the risk of unauthorised access or disclosure.

_Can I find out the personal data that the organisation holds about me?_

Firstsource Solutions UK Limited at your request, can confirm what information we hold about you and how it is processed. If Firstsource Solutions UK Limited does hold personal data about you, you can request the following information:

  * Identity and the contact details of the person or organisation that has determined how and why to process your data. In some cases, this will be a representative in the EU.
  * Contact details of the data protection officer, where applicable.
  * The purpose of the processing as well as the legal basis for processing.
  * If the processing is based on the legitimate interests of Firstsource Solutions UK Limited or a third party, information about those interests.
  * The categories of personal data collected, stored and processed.
  * Recipient(s) or categories of recipients that the data is/will be disclosed to.
  * If we intend to transfer the personal data to a third country or international organisation, information about how we ensure this is done securely. The EU has approved sending personal data to some countries because they meet a minimum standard of data protection. In other cases, we will ensure there are specific measures in place to secure your information.
  * How long the data will be stored.
  * Details of your rights to correct, erase, restrict or object to such processing.
  * Information about your right to withdraw consent at any time.
  * How to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.
  * Whether the provision of personal data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract, as well as whether you are obliged to provide the personal data and the possible consequences of failing to provide such data.
  * The source of personal data if it wasn’t collected directly from you.
  * Any details and information of automated decision making, such as profiling, and any meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and expected consequences of such processing.

_What forms of ID will I need to provide in order to access this?_

Firstsource Solutions UK Limited accepts the following forms of ID when information on your personal data is requested:

Passport, driving licence, birth certificate, utility bill (from last 3 months).

_Contact details of the Data Protection Officer:_

** ** | **Data Protection Officer contact details**  
---|---  
Contact Name: | Data Protection Officer  
Address line 1: | Space One  
Address line 2: | 1 Beadon Road  
Address line 3: | London  
Address line 4: | W6 0EA  
  
Disclaimer

## Disclaimer

The information contained in this website is for general information purposes only. While Firstsource Solutions Limited (‘we’) endeavor to keep the information up-to-date and correct, we make no representations or warranties of any kind, express or implied, about the completeness, accuracy, reliability, suitability or availability, with respect to the website, of the information, services, or related graphics contained in the website for any purpose. Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk.

This site is subject to periodic update and revision. Materials should only be considered current as of the date of initial publication appearing thereon, without regard to the date on which you may access the information. We maintain the right to delete or modify information on this website without prior notice to any third party or person and shall maintain a complete discretion on the content published.

In no event shall we be liable for any loss or damage including without limitation any direct, indirect, special, or consequential loss or damage, loss of data, profits, business, reputation or any loss or damage whatsoever arising out of, or in connection with, the use of this website or any information contained herein.

Past financial performance should not be taken as an indication or guarantee of future performance and no representation and warranty, express or implied, is made regarding future performance.

Every effort is made to keep the website up and running. However, we take no responsibility for, and will not be liable for, the website being temporarily unavailable due to technical issues beyond our control. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to correct any errors or omissions in any portion of the website. Any unauthorized use of this website may give rise to a claim for damages including criminal prosecution.

Unless otherwise stated, we or our licensors, as the case maybe own all intellectual property rights in the website and any information or material on the website. All our intellectual property rights in relation to the website are reserved.

Subject to the terms and conditions set forth herein, We will grant a non-exclusive, non-transferable, limited right to access this site and the materials thereon.

You agree not to:

  * Interrupt or attempt to interrupt the operation of the site in any way.
  * Intrude or attempt to intrude into the site in any way.
  * Post any obscene, defamatory or annoying materials on the site.
  * Obscure any material, including this notice, already posted on the site.
  * Use the site or any contents thereof to defame, intimidate, annoy or otherwise cause nuisance or breach the rights of any person.

This disclaimer will be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of India, and any disputes relating to the website or this disclaimer shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts in Mumbai, India.
